George Kleine Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1886-1946 (Box 1-67)
  - United Theatre Equipment Corp. (Box 59)
    - Matters, Thomas H., Jr., 1923-1927
    - Merger, 1923
    - Miscellaneous matters, 1923-1926
    - Rose & Paskus, 1923-1927
    - Sales, circa 1920-1922, undated
    - Shares, 1917-1923
    - Sloane and Chase Manufacturing Co., 1922-1923
    - Stockholders, directors, minutes of meetings, etc., 1922-1924
    - Transactions, 1916-1920
  - University of Kansas, Lawrence, Kans. See Container 41, same heading (Box 62)
  - University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah See Container 41, same heading
  - University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wis., 1921-1928 See also Container 42, same heading
  - The Unwritten Code (Inter-Ocean Film Corp.), 1920-1922
  - Urban, Charles, 1923, 1925
  - Valentino, Rudolph, 1925-1926, (2 folders)
  - Vendetta, 1914-1922
  - Vanity Fair, 1915-1926
  - Vanoscope Co., 1913
  - Variety, 1926
  - Victor Animatograph Co., 1923-1930
  - Victor Safety Cinema Corp., 1920-1923
  - Viking Blade Co., 1929
  - Virginia (educational distribution of films), 1923-1930
  - Visual education, 1926 (Box 63)
  - Visual Instruction Association of New York City, 1922-1923 See also Container 42, Visual Instruction Association of New York City and National Academy of Visual Instruction
  - Vitagraph Co. of America, 1922
  - Vitagraph-Lubin-Selig-Essanay, 1916
  - Vitaphone, 1926
  - Vogel, William, 1929
  - Voorhis, Otie, 1927-1929
  - Voris, William (Spitzer, Rorick & Co.), 1915-1919
  - Wainwright (J. G. & R. B.), Ltd. (Officer 666), 1920
  - Warde, Arthur F. (Film Co. of Ireland), 1919-1922
  - Warren (F. B.) Corp., 1921-1923, 1928
  - Waters, Percival L. See Container 63, same heading
  - Watson, Harry, Jr., 1916, undated See also Container 4, Bickel, George, and Harry Watson, Jr.
  - Wellington, 1919
  - Werren, Sam (United Film Service), 1922
  - Wertheimer, E., 1915-1919
  - Wescott Film Corp., 1919-1920
  - Western Photogravure Co., 1918-1923
  - Western Star Feature Co., 1921-1922
  - Wheeler, L. C., 1918-1920
  - White, Francis D., 1922-1923
  - White, James A.
  - Wholesome Film Service, 1923
  - Widescope Camera Co., 1919-1920
  - Wid Gunning, Inc., 1922 (Box 64)
  - Wild Oats, 1916-1928
  - Wilk, Jacob, 1921
  - Williams, Mrs. Sumner (Juliet), 1925
  - Williamson (J. C.) Ltd. (Australian and South African theaters), 1915
  - Wilson, Eska (Standard Motion Picture Service, 1921-1922
  - Wilson Film Co., 1919-1920
  - Window Opposite (schedule of cost), circa 1918
  - Wisby, Hrolf (pre-visualization plan), 1926
  - Wolf, Nathan See Container 33, Wolf, Nathan, and Morris Choynski
  - The Woman Next Door, 1921
  - The Woman Who Dared, 1921
  - World Film Corp.
    - General, 1919-1925, (2 folders)
    - Accounting, 1919-1920 (Box 65)
    - Charlie Chaplin films, 1919
    - Contract, 1919
    - Republic Distributing Corp. (Kleine claim against), 1919-1921
    - The Unwritten Code and The Girl Alaska (accounts), 1919-1922
  - World War I
    - Aid and gifts by George Kleine, 1918
    - Canada, 1918-1919
    - Committee on Public Information, 1917-1918
    - Employees in United States Military and other service, 1917-1919
    - Italian war pictures, 1918, undated
    - Liberty Loan, 1917-1920, undated, (3 folders) (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous, 1915-1922, undated, (3 folders)
    - Motion pictures, 1918
    - Postwar Americanization, 1920-1923
    - Taxes, 1917-1922, (2 folders) (Box 67)
    - The Unbeliever, 1918
    - War Camp Motion Picture Committee, 1917-1918
    - War Industries Board, 1917-1918
  - Wright, Wilbur See Container 1, Airplanes and Wilbur Wright
  - Xydias, Anthony, 1915-1916
  - Your Obedient Servant, 1920-1922, (2 folders)
  - Zezza, Baron A., 1914-1916
- Inventories and Lists, circa 1900-1945 (Box 68-70)
  Lists and inventories of film titles, release schedules, prints, negatives, and other material with related correspondence.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material.
  - Advertised in Motion Picture News (titles, authors, directors), Mar.-Apr. 1920 (Box 68)
  - “Around the World in 52 Reels of Film” (advertisement)
  - Classic series glass negatives
  - Conquest Films, 1918-1921
  - Copyrighted films (select list, 1913-1916 )
  - Edison-Kleine Features
  - Edison negatives, 1917, 1919
  - Edison schedules A-D, F-H, K-M (with titles and release dates), 1915-1920, undated
  - Edison unreleased subjects, 1920, undated
  - Educational distribution
    - Campbell County High School, Gillette, Wyo., 1930
    - Central High School, Scranton, Pa., 1929-1930
    - Iowa State College, Ames, Iowa, 1930
    - State College of Washington, Pullman, Wash., 1927-1930
    - University of California, Berkeley, Calif., 1922-1930
    - University of Colorado, Boulder, Colo., 1922-1928
    - University of Hawaii, Honolulu, 1930
    - University of Indiana, Bloomington, Ind., 1921-1928
    - University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa, 1921-1928
    - University of Kansas, Lawrence, Kans., 1921-1928, [1930?]
    - University of Oklahoma, Norman, Okla., 1925
    - University of Texas, Austin, Tex., 1924-1928
    - University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah, 1925-1928
    - University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wis., 1921-1928, 1925-1928
    - Ursuline Academy, Cleveland, Ohio, 1930
  - Empire City Film Laboratory, 1919-1929
  - Feature release chart, 1927 (Box 69)
  - Feature releases, [1913?], 1917
  - Films bought, returned, held for consideration
  - Furniture, 1924-1926
  - George Kleine Cycle of Film Classics (brochures)
  - Griffen-owned films, circa 1915
  - Historical films, [1900?], [1924?]
  - Lombard, Ill., storage facility, 1923, 1927
  - Manuscript files, 1927
  - Manuscripts sent to Selig, 1928
  - Master inventory of Kleine records, 1919, 1924
  - Miscellaneous, 1917-1929
  - National Archives (films selected for archival value), [1945?]
  - Negatives, 1918, 1922, undated
  - Old cold foreign copies, 1919
  - Perfection pictures
  - Prints, 1919-1928
  - Publicity stills, 1924, 1927
  - “The Roosevelt Series of History and Biography,” [1912?]
  - Schedule of releases, 1913-1918
  - Sixteen millimeter special subjects, circa 1930
  - Statement of amounts for extra footage credited to manufacturers, 1910-1914
  - Story rights
  - Teitel (A.) Vaults, 1923-1930 (Box 70)
  - Thirty Years Ago, 1928
  - Titles, 1913-1928
  - Toronto and Montreal, circa 1920
  - United States Congress, House of Representatives, Committee on Ways and Means (educational motion pictures imported by George Kleine), 1913
  - Value per reel, 1919
  - Watson, Henry (comedies in Chicago, Ill.), 1925
- Distribution File, 1920-1932 (Box 71-77)
  Correspondence, financial records, and other items relating to the distribution of motion pictures.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material or geographic location.
  - “A” miscellaneous (Box 71)
  - Foreign
    - Australia, 1926-1930
    - Bahamas, 1926-1928
    - Belgium, 1926-1928
    - Canada, 1923-1930
    - China, 1921
    - Czechoslovakia, 1928
    - England, 1925, 1929
    - Finland, 1929
    - France, 1923-1928
    - Greece, 1920-1921
    - India, 1925-1928
    - Japan, 1922-1929
    - New Zealand, 1927-1929
    - Philippines, 1922-1925
    - Puerto Rico, 1922-1927
    - Spain, 1928
  - Fox, William (Fox Films, Fox Theatres), 1930
  - “K” miscellaneous
  - Kleine credit accounts, 1927-1930
  - “L” miscellaneous
  - Service Film Corp., 1925
  - Sound devices, 1928
  - Spoor, George K., 1925-1929
  - Staehli, Edward, 1924, 1930
  - States
    - Alabama, 1922-1929
    - Arizona, 1927-1929
    - Arkansas, 1922-1929
    - California, 1922-1931, (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - Colorado, 1923-1930
    - Connecticut, 1925-1929
    - Delaware, 1928-1930
    - District of Columbia, 1925-1929
    - Florida, 1921-1930
    - Georgia, 1926-1929
    - Hawaii, 1923-1930
    - Idaho, 1922
    - Illinois, 1922-1930
    - Indiana, 1922-1929, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Iowa
      - Iowa State College, Ames, 1927-1931
      - Miscellaneous, 1929-1930
      - State University of Iowa, Iowa City, 1924-1929
    - Kansas, 1923-1931, (2 folders)
    - Kentucky, 1921-1929
    - Louisiana, 1922-1929
    - Maine, 1926-1929
    - Maryland, 1925-1929
    - Massachusetts, 1921-1930, (2 folders)
      - Detroit public schools, 1925-1929 (Box 74)
      - Miscellaneous, 1922-1930
    - Minnesota
      - Miscellaneous, 1921-1930
      - University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, 1922-1927
    - Mississippi, 1922-1930
    - Missouri, 1922-1930
    - Montana, 1923-1929
    - Nebraska, 1922-1929
    - New Hampshire, 1923-1929
    - New Jersey, 1925-1930
    - New Mexico, 1927
    - New York, 1924-1930, (2 folders)
    - North Carolina, 1921-1930 (Box 75)
    - North Dakota, 1922-1929
    - Ohio
      - Miscellaneous, 1921-1930, (2 folders)
      - Riegel, Vernon M., 1926-1930
    - Oklahoma, 1921-1930
    - Oregon, 1921-1929 (Box 76)
    - Pennsylvania, 1925-1930, (2 folders)
    - Rhode Island, 1927
    - South Carolina, 1929-1930
    - South Dakota, 1922-1927
    - Tennessee, 1926-1930
    - Texas, 1922-1931
    - Utah, 1921-1929
    - Vermont, 1925-1929 (Box 77)
    - Virginia, 1929-1930
    - Washington, 1921-1932
    - West Virginia, 1926-1929
    - Wisconsin, 1927-1930
    - Wyoming, 1927-1930
    - Miscellaneous
  - Stern Brothers, 1928-1929
  - Tichenor, Frank A., 1923-1927
  - Verhoeven, John A., 1924-1928
  - Victor Animatograph Co., 1930
  - Western Union Telegraph Co., 1929-1930
  - Zincograph Co., 1926-1928